There is competition for currency.
If your currency is only available in all banks,
from Monday to Friday, they close at 4 p.m.
No one wants to use your money.
If you can get your salary paid every day or every hour,
rather than being paid at the end of the month,
that's something which allows you to spend money,
but that's also something which allows you to essentially
get more efficient economy, more efficient mortgage.
If DeFi is only about sending money quick, that's good.
But that's not good enough.
On privacy and CBDCs, I think people need to be honest.
You don't have privacy today.
If you're in crypto, chances are you found yourself thinking,
why is DeFi so complicated?
Well, if that resonates with you, then you're in the right place.
In this video, we've got Charles, the CEO of DYDX Foundation,
to explain what's going on with DeFi right now
and how you can easily stake on DYDX and start earning USDC stablecoin today.
If you're in crypto for the long run, you will find this very valuable.
How are you? Good morning.
Good morning to you. You look great.
You are the CEO of DYDX.
And I think a lot of people want to know what's your journey like.
How did you become the CEO?
I started my kind of journey in crypto in 2011 when I discovered Bitcoin.
Before discovering Bitcoin, I was deep into peer-to-peer file sharing.
So I was very familiar with peer-to-peer computing overall.
And then someone forwarded to me the Bitcoin white paper,
which was mentioning peer-to-peer money.
So I was thinking, oh, peer-to-peer something.
I'm very excited. I want more of peer-to-peer.
I realized that actually I was understanding the technical aspect of it,
but I had to learn much more about money.
I was using money every day, of course,
but I was not understanding money that much.
That's really what Bitcoin brings me to study further.
I actually bought my first Bitcoin on Taobao.
Because at the time, in 2011, there was only one exchange.
It was Mongcox in Japan.
And it was very, very complicated.
So one day I asked my wife.
She was on Taobao doing some shopping.
And I told her, do they have Bitcoin on Taobao?
And she asked me, how do you spell? Let me check.
We find some people selling Bitcoin.
So I bought Bitcoin.
At the time, that's the only way I found to get my first Bitcoin.
So I sold my Bitcoin the same year.
That's a mistake I just had to accept.
It was a little bit wide for me.
It was a big surprise.
I got busy with my company, my business, and my family.
It was taking too much of my time.
Plus, the asset was extremely volatile.
So I said, listen, focus on what you have to do today and forget this thing.
So I sold everything the same year.
Fast forward, I worked for the Hong Kong government.
I was head of fintech for the Hong Kong government,
helping of kind of building the fintech financial technology ecosystem in Hong Kong.
At the time, I built a team of 10 people with offices in Beijing, in Hong Kong,
obviously in London, in San Francisco.
The most promising fintech companies from the world to Hong Kong,
to use Hong Kong as a stepping stone for expanding in Asia.
In this context, I made a company called ConsenSys.
ConsenSys is a company behind MetaMask.
And fast forward, I eventually joined ConsenSys to create the ConsenSys Hong Kong office.
And later, I was in charge of Asia for ConsenSys,
working with the MetaMask team, working with Infura.
I built a lot of CBDCs, central banks, digital currencies.
My team at the time was actively building six different projects for central banks,
from Australia to Hong Kong to Abu Dhabi and Korea.
We had a lot of fun talking about, obviously, blockchain and crypto,
but deep diving into the infrastructure.
And I joined DYDX about one year and a half ago.
I wanted to kind of evolve in my next job into something new.
I spend a lot of time in the space already.
I learn a lot and I want to learn more.
The proposition of DYDX was very interesting for me.
So I spend a lot of time on Bitcoin.
I guess I understand Bitcoin.
I was working for ConsenSys, one of the largest blockchain engineering companies
in the world with a focus on Ethereum.
So I understand Ethereum as well.
But when the opportunity of DYDX came up,
it was very interesting for me to get my hands on the app chain narrative,
the application chains.
When a project is large enough to build its own chain,
so that was one aspect of it.
Exploring the stack of Cosmos as a Cosmos SDK
and how this kind of very strong candidate for being the leader in technology as well
is evolving and learning by building.
That's something which I think works very well for me.
And working on DeFi, moving my kind of experience up the stack at the application level.
And DeFi is a very well-established use case, right?
Wow, that's a crazy ride.
You've done literally everything.
Let's say before crypto, you were in fintech.
There has to be something about DeFi that is very appealing to you.
What is it?
Why DeFi?
DeFi means access.
Getting access to a mobile phone wallet, getting access to a credit card is normal
and it's not a luxury anymore.
But the reality is the world is rich of 7 billion people
and many of them don't have access to that yet.
So for me, DeFi is access.
The same way the internet gave access globally to knowledge
and allows us to learn, to communicate.
In money, we still have like kind of silos.
There's a Eurozone, the people in Europe with enough money.
There is the Chinese space.
There is some other parts.
It's still very much silos, right?
DeFi means access.
DeFi means efficiency.
If you have a chance to travel a little bit or do some international business,
you quickly realize that the financial system is highly inefficient.
And I still cannot believe why when I send money across the world with my bank,
it takes two, three days.
They always have an explanation for me.
But to be honest with you, this explanation is not good enough.
We have the technology available today and it's still a legacy system.
And behind that, there is this concept in DeFi of composability.
And that's where I'm very excited also about DeFi is.
And we see that with many projects.
If you're deep in crypto, it's every day.
But I think the opportunity of DeFi is really bringing innovations to the masses.
To come back to composability, essentially in the world of smart contracts and permissionless
blockchains, start to build some products on the top of someone else without having to
give away all your power or your profits or anything like this to them.
It's really like some kind of money legal, you know?
This aspect, it's really opens the opportunities, opens the space for innovation as well.
So access, efficiency and innovation.
This is what DeFi means for me.
Of course, we are still in the early days of DeFi.
It's still very speculative.
It's still very looking at crypto assets only.
But we see that changing.
We see stable coins coming in.
We see real world assets slowly coming in.
We see the audience growing also.
So I think the early adopters of DeFi are very early adopters.
But then when the mass expands, it comes with different people using DeFi for different
things.
In terms of timeline, I think we need to be realistic, not going through too much wishful
thinking.
DeFi is growing.
It's growing fast.
But there is no reason for it to be mass market before five to 10 years.
So that's your timeline, five to 10 years?
Five to 10 years.
If you look at the speed of adoption of the internet, it took almost 10 years, right?
Some parts of the world went very, very fast.
Some others took more time.
So I think we will see part of the world and probably Asia going on DeFi much faster than
other places.
The financial system is kind of OK today or is good enough for some people.
They don't have the excitement that we have to use this kind of innovation.
So if I speak to my wife, she's fantastic, but she's happy with her debit card and mobile
wallet.
And you need to bring something really unique.
You can convince people using the current system to move to DeFi.
I mean, there is plenty of people and very talented people working on DeFi innovation
where we should be looking for ideas in blockchain.
And ideas which resonate with users is simply by looking at fintech.
The fintech industry has been active on refreshing the money systems for many years and very successfully,
specifically in Asia.
I think fintech means something in Asia.
Fintech in Europe or in the US is very deceptive.
I might have a bias.
I spend much time in Asia.
But I think in Asia, there is clearly very strong fintech and very strong propositions.
I think for us in crypto, we should be looking at what has been working well in fintech and
trying to pick those winners and kind of improve them further with crypto.
That's probably the fastest path to find product market fit and accelerate the growth of the
user base of crypto and DeFi.
So people say this DeFi thing eventually take over the traditional finance because it's not
efficient enough.
What's your take on this?
I think it will.
We will not realize it.
If DeFi was to have a strategy, we should do it very quietly and very humbly to make
sure that the people get to use DeFi, but in a very smooth way.
The reality, most people don't want to have one more wallet.
Most people don't want to deal with private keys.
DeFi is still a complex process today.
What I hope is to see DeFi happening very quietly, but everywhere, essentially.
And how it can come, if you look at the agenda of central banks today, I can safely say 100%
of the central banks in the world, if not 99%, are working on CBDCs, central bank digital
currencies.
What they're doing is essentially they're putting the central bank money on blockchain
in order to move it faster and to be cross-border and to make sure their currency remains competitive.
There is competition for currency.
If your currency is only available in all banks from Monday to Friday, they close at
4 p.m.
No one wants to use your money because your money is not practical.
It's strategic and urgent for central banks to essentially make sure people want to use
their money.
Otherwise, the currency will lose traction, right?
So my point being, central banks are building on blockchain for the most part.
So I think we will start to see some projects using components of DeFi for CBDCs.
And DeFi will come in the life of people in multiple ways.
One illustration of that is a central bank project in Hong Kong, the innovation hub from
the BIS and the HKMA and some others.
Essentially, and PDOC China, actually.
So I was working on this project some time ago.
What is interesting is they essentially build a blockchain infrastructure under their own
terms.
So that's probably a great path forward.
And then they pick some smart contract concepts of swapping, for example, CBDCs against one
another.
So DeFi is coming.
Definitely.
It's going to take more time than people expect.
I don't think people will all be using USDC.
They will be using also their domestic central bank tokens.
Will they mix together?
I don't know.
But I think this kind of innovation, which will happen on the background, will definitely
come.
And people might come into DeFi via video games.
In Asia, there is a big industry of video games.
So people might first get like some NFTs or some digital assets for video games and soon
realize, oh, I can put money on it also.
And I can put this money to work.
I can do some lending.
I can do different activities.
And this kind of path to customer acquisition is also interesting.
If you can get your salary paid every day or every hour rather than being paid at the
end of the month, that's something which allows you to spend money.
But that's also something which allows you to essentially get more efficient economy, more
efficient mortgage.
Today, it's very kind of binary.
You work 30 days, you get paid.
But if you look at FinTech, you can get essentially the promise of your salary at the end of the
month or maybe the promise of your salary every day being sold to a bank or being sold to
a smart contract system to optimize the kind of capital use and make it more efficient.
So this is kind of very new things we bring people in.
If DeFi is only about sending money quick, that's good.
But that's not good enough.
People will not change up on their phone for that.
Money is already fairly quick.
But if you can make some value propositions which are very strong, you're going to be paid
every day, not at the end of the month anymore.
And maybe you can use your salary smart contract to get a better mortgage, for example, or to
get the money in advance.
That's something which has very strong capital use features, which bring something very new.
That is very interesting because I was going to ask you, how do you actually attract more
people into DeFi?
And I think you just answered the question is maybe not label it as DeFi so people think
it's so hard.
It's more like how can they actually use it in their daily lives and make it better?
We need to be patient.
DeFi is part of Web3.
And if you look at the way the internet grew over the years, it took a long time.
And the internet at the beginning, I'm 46 years old.
So I used the internet in the very, very early days with phone lines and very slow speed
and all these things.
DeFi has the internet take time for the technology to improve, for the user experience to improve
as well.
I think what many people should be doing is simplifying the UX by an order of magnitude
and trying to really make clear with themselves, is my product for the DGEMs or is my product
hoping to go mainstream?
I think that's what, for example, Uniswap is doing very well.
If you go on Uniswap, it's very simple.
You have some tokens.
We want to sell it.
Here is a price click here.
If you go on some other exchanges, they give you all kinds of order types, all kinds of
leverage.
The screen is full of buttons.
It's for a very specific type of users, right?
And DYDX is a very good example.
But you need to be clear, honest, and opinionated about who are you targeting and what do they
want exactly.
After you get this kind of clarity in your mind about your target audience, it's way
easier to make things really dedicated to that.
Can I ask you a question on CBDC?
So I've heard a lot of different mixed opinions on CBDC.
Some people think, you know, it's governments growing more control on the people.
And what's your take on this whole CBDC situation?
It's very much a polarizing topic indeed.
My take is CBDCs are necessary for economies.
CBDCs are necessary for many countries and currencies.
If you're paid today in a currency which is not modern enough, your currency will depreciate.
This is just the forces of the market.
On privacy and CBDCs, I think people need to be honest.
You don't have privacy today.
If you're using a mobile phone wallet, if you're using a credit card, at any point in
time, if you are misbehaving, any police department in any country can give a call to the bank
or the credit card issuer and saying, oh, please, can we get the details of Charles' latest
transactions?
Because it's kind of suspicious.
So there is no privacy today already.
So don't worry more.
I think you have to be honest about that.
And it's just going to make also things more efficient by having a better money experience
and bringing maybe bits and pieces of DeFi innovation.
So I'm excited about CBDCs.
I hope the CBDCs will be sitting on permissionless blockchain.
CBDCs will first live on private blockchains.
So private blockchains will essentially enable banks and banks will get some kind of private
blockchain between the banks.
The central banks have to protect also the banks, right?
Banks are important.
Banks are doing a job.
So I think the next step of CBDCs is faster adoptions and usage at the wholesale level between
banks.
And later, I hope CBDCs will come into permissionless chain, meaning I can really move my money everywhere
without having the latency, the unknown benefit of using a bank in the middle, unless a bank
really brings some serious advantages.
It's a hard mission for central banks.
So they need to organize as a technology.
They need to convince the commercial banks and within their country to be part of the project,
have them excited and making sure that the commercial banks are implementing it.
Many people don't realize, but many projects at central banks are not successful.
And CBDCs is a strategy for the central banks.
So they really want this CBDCs project to be successful.
But when you speak to a bank, which is making money through inefficiencies, when you speak
to a bank, which is sometimes 300,000 employees, which is a very old and slow moving organization,
it's not an easy job.
I'm excited about CBDCs.
I think privacy is something of concern, but people should not be naive about it.
And privacy, as in many countries, there is already privacy laws and CBDCs will need
to follow these existing laws of privacy.
And then it's going to bring just more efficient and more fair ecosystem by building a better
infrastructure in a fintech ecosystem.
So when central banks build CBDCs and they build an open system, they give fair chances
between banks and fintech startup.
OK.
If you have the right infrastructure, the financial infrastructure on which everyone can come
and plug in.
It's not happening in many countries.
One very good example of this fair and highly competitive financial ecosystem is India.
India has been implementing UPI, which is essentially a payment API at a very, very large scale.
So a bank and a startup can compete with the same tools.
Wow.
And CBDCs can be in this kind of era where central banks by technology bring fairness to
the market.
Why many financial systems are not innovative anymore?
Because they belong to 25, 50 banks.
And these banks are slow and they don't have any advantages in bringing innovation.
But one way for central banks to kind of check their ecosystem is bringing technology for
fair access.
And then a small company can provide similar service to a big company.
And then you bring competition again.
And competition is good for users, for pricing, for everyone.
I love that.
And I feel like all these different industries and different experiences you have has given
your current company, DYDX, a fresh breeze.
What does DYDX do?
DYDX is a DeFi project started in 2018 by Antonio Giuliano, which is a former Convays engineer.
And DYDX is today the world's largest decentralized exchange protocol for crypto derivatives.
So let me unpack that because there is a lot of complex words here.
So in the world of crypto trading, there is two different types of venues where people
can buy and sell or express their opinion on the market.
You can go to a centralized exchange like Binance, Convays and many others.
Or you can go to a decentralized exchange like Uniswap, DYDX and many others as well.
Centralized exchanges belong to one company as they are sitting in one database only and
they organize the trading.
They're kind of very similar to a traditional bank, to be honest.
And then decentralized exchanges are essentially very lean organization.
Smart contracts are managing all the different flows within those exchanges.
So DYDX is a decentralized exchange.
It sits on the blockchain.
That's one thing.
The second thing is in crypto and in general market overall, people have the opportunity
when they can and when they decide to, you can either trade spots.
So you can buy the real asset, you can trade spot Ethereum, you can trade spot Bitcoin and
receive a Bitcoin or receive an ETH and put it into your wallet.
That's spot trading.
And then there is another part of finance, which is what we call derivative.
And derivative allows you to express your opinion in very different ways.
Rather than just buying as the asset, you can express your opinion and essentially taking
some kind of bet as saying, OK, I believe that Bitcoin will keep growing in value over
the next hours, days, months, and then take a bet on this with some leverage and being
bullish or bearish on one asset.
And the reality is that the derivative on futures markets are 10 times bigger than spot markets.
So every time there is a Bitcoin which is exchanged on centralized exchanges as a spot, there is
10 times more Bitcoin being exchanged in the derivative market.
So DYDX is a decentralized exchange focusing on derivative.
And we are the number one globally.
We are bigger than Uniswap.
It's a project which is led by the community, by some companies.
It's a decentralized open source DeFi protocol focusing on crypto derivatives.
Like you said, you guys are the biggest and you have the biggest market share on DeFi
derivatives.
What do you think you did right?
And what led to this kind of success?
That's a great question.
DYDX started its history on Ethereum and then was one of the very early adopters of layer
twos.
Layer twos are all over the place today.
But DYDX kind of migrated to layer two very early on.
So I think what DYDX did well was always to assess the technology available in our space
and being blockchain agnostic.
If the community decides to change the underlying blockchain technology, that's perfectly fine.
So Ethereum went from Ethereum to layer two.
And now the DYDX has its own blockchain, the DYDX chain.
So I think what DYDX did well over time was to be kind of technology agnostic and product
first.
Very simple, but very efficient.
The second thing DYDX has been doing well is extreme focus.
DYDX only works on derivatives.
This is where the attention of everyone is crypto derivative, period.
Nothing else.
No spot, no options, no NFTs, no whatever is under the sun.
We see many projects having sometimes a slow start and starting to diversify.
DYDX had a good start, but I think the response was very good because the focus was extremely
clear.
So being agnostic in technology, being laser focused on one use case only and trying to
be the best in the world for this focus.
And that's what DYDX has been delivering.
And now that the DYDX ecosystem has moved to the DYDX chain, it really enables a lot of the
technology and kind of shared innovation to be happening.
So we see that through the DYDX governance, where people and the users of the protocol
can decide on new listings.
They can use different voting and governance mechanism to upgrade the protocol as a group
in a very decentralized manner.
I was talking to this very important person from your team, Hisashi, and he said, you are
aiming to list 500 tokens on DYDX by the end of this year.
This is the beauty of DYDX also.
It's extremely decentralized now.
And the decisions and the focus and the strategy is defined by the community.
So essentially, the community can launch new markets just by voting on them.
And the software has been made in a way that anything that has a healthy price feed can
potentially be listed.
So we expect in the coming weeks, a lot of different governance votes.
We see conversations on the forum, DYDX.forum, of people asking and kind of preparing listings
of new assets.
So that's a very exciting part.
More trading pairs.
And also, I think one piece of technology which is coming for the DYDX ecosystem and many
different groups are working on this topic is what we call the permissionless market.
So permissionless market means that the users of DYDX can list new markets in a permissionless
way.
And that's a very strong proposition also.
There is no lord.
There is no master.
The master is essentially the governance and the users.
And when you give the right tools and when you define the good risk framework as well
as liquidity framework, you can really have a very interesting new marketplace where the
pace of new listings is faster.
The pace of delisting is also efficient to make sure that you don't keep some markets
which are not healthy anymore.
More crypto native assets, that's for sure.
But we can think of new type of assets such as indexes, for example, of crypto assets,
carbon credits, other commodities.
Think of all the commodities which are traded today in the Chicago Stock Exchange.
Think of cacao, sugar, corn, and so on.
This is a marketplace which is kind of a closed door marketplace.
You need to be qualified in a certain type of company to be able to trade.
Bringing the access to the world to this kind of trading, if that's possible and compliant,
I think that's a very strong new proposition.
You guys launched a chain of your own last year in October.
And for the first time, DYDX is fully decentralized.
What does that mean for the general user?
For example, if I'm a user of a DEX, what I care about is if it's easy to use, if it's
liquid.
What does this decentralized mean for me?
What it means, so maybe just to give some background, I'll be a bit technical here,
but hopefully this is useful and understandable.
The version 3 of DYDX, which was sitting on Ethereum, mainnet and Ethereum layer tools
don't have the throughput and the capacity to host on-chain an order book.
The order book is where the buy orders and the sell orders match and the price gets discovered
essentially.
On the Ethereum version of DYDX, the order book was always hosted off-chain on an AWS server.
On the new DYDX, sitting on DYDX chain is fully decentralized now.
So the order book is not into a private server anymore.
The order book is now essentially hosted by the validators in their memory.
So what it means for you is you don't have any last question mark on the transparency of
the marketplace.
You don't have any questions on, is my order really matched the right way?
Is someone trading against me?
It was not happening before, but the point is now it's obvious and it's visible for
everyone.
If you go, for example, trading on Coinbase or Binance or Wabi or whatever centralized exchanges,
you might have the question, what's happening exactly at the exchange?
If I want to buy at $1, is someone buying before me?
There is no way you will know.
It's a black box.
I'm not saying they're doing anything wrong, but I'm saying we don't know.
We cannot see that.
With the evolution of DYDX today as a DeFi user, it means that you can totally get an understanding
of the marketplace.
It brings some value for different types of users.
So for the general users of DYDX, they know that the marketplace is actually very healthy
and totally transparent now.
From A to Z, you see everything.
That's really exciting.
Number two kind of benefit is more for the hedge funds, institutionals, market makers,
users, or what we call prosumers, users with a strong experience and very kind of complex
and mature way of trading.
They get to understand the marketplace.
Many of them are using bots.
Many of them are using AI or machine learning to understand the market and trade on the market
at a high frequency and with very complex type of strategies.
When you get to understand the marketplace, when you get to understand the order book,
you can design much more efficient and creative ways of expressing your opinion on the market,
i.e. trading.
It's not possible if you are building an algorithm trading in front of a black box.
It's like you're trying to guess with your eyes not seeing anything.
Covered, yeah.
So it's really very interesting.
The users get a more fair marketplace and more visible marketplace.
And the power users get also a new world where they can really deep dive into the market.
So the proposition of DYDX is very strong.
This is why we see the growth we are seeing today.
More than 20 billion, sorry, of trading volumes on the protocol since the launch of DYDX.
It's this aspect of transparency and kind of new experience.
For the normal user in terms of UI and UX, more or less the same, honestly, no big change.
That's a very big talent of the DYDX engineers is they are able to bring you very groundbreaking
innovation without disturbing your kind of experience, just improving it.
Can you tell us what validators or stakers are?
Because I know that your trading fee actually goes to them instead of going to the exchange.
The DYDX chain is run by 60 different validators.
It's an application chain.
Essentially, when these validators kind of make this running, they enable the DYDX exchange
and the DYDX protocol itself.
These validators receive DYDX tokens from stakers.
So you and me and anyone can essentially decide to bring the DYDX token and stake them to validators.
These validators have two missions, verifying the chain and minting new blocks.
So that's a very classic kind of mission for validators.
And the number two mission for validators is to essentially host the order book and update
the order book so that the order book gets distributed and efficient.
As a staker, you can stake with using your Ledger hardware wallet, for example, and directly
stake in a pure DeFi way your tokens to a validator.
And as you mentioned earlier, one of the big innovation of DYDX is that community decided
via a governance route to redistribute 100% of the fees collected by the exchange to validators
and stakers.
So today, when you stake your DYDX on the DYDX chain, you get rewarded in USDC, not in
DYDX tokens, in USDC.
And where are these USDC coming from?
It comes from the users of the DYDX exchange.
So when you trade on DYDX, you pay trading fees, and these trading fees are paid in USDC.
And 100% of the fees paid by the users are going directly to the stakers via the validators.
And you also have a certification.
And you can also use the market.
And you can also use the other side.
7 個步驟
先在交易所買 DYDX 代幣
然後把代幣轉到以太坊區塊鏈上
但記得 Charles 說 DYDX 自己做了一個區塊鏈對吧
所以我們要再把 DYDX 的代幣
從以太坊區塊鏈跨鏈到 DYDX 鏈上
接著就可以質押了
他的質押之所以受歡迎
是因為最後拿到的獎勵會是 USDC 穩定幣
而且是隨時可以提令
感覺起來很複雜吧
但是基本上能聽過一次就會了
我先到 OKX 交易所買了 DYDX 代幣
BigEd 交易所之後也會有
去中心化交易所 Osmosis 也是可以買得到
把小狐狸 MetaMask 錢包複製到你以太坊的區塊鏈錢包位置
注意左上角是 Ethereum Mainnet 以太坊的區塊鏈
再來回到 OKX 交易所提幣 DYDX 的頁面
把剛剛複製好的 MetaMask 以太坊錢包地址貼上去
確定提幣
回到小狐狸 MetaMask 的錢包
這時候 DYDX 可能還沒有出現
確定一下左上還是以太坊 Ethereum Mainnet
看到 Import Token 輸入代幣
這裡就會看到剛剛轉進來的 DYDX
成功出現在小狐狸 MetaMask 的錢包裡面
接下來的步驟可能會需要一些
以太幣來當作手續費
如果你的小狐狸 MetaMask 的錢包裡面沒有以太幣
那就跟剛剛轉這個 DYDX 的步驟是一樣的
現在 OKX 買這個 以太幣 ETH
轉進來當手續費
大概買個 10 塊錢美金以內就可以了
再來我們要把小狐狸 以太坊錢包裡面的 DYDX
轉到 DYDX 鏈上了
來到 bridge.dydx.trade
我會把這個連結貼在資訊欄
請務必確認它是正確的網址
連結小狐狸 MetaMask 錢包
這裡就會顯示了 ETH DYDX 的數量
也就是說
在以太坊鏈上的 DYDX 代幣數量
這些代幣都轉到 DYDX 區塊鏈上
確認之後你就會看到
Sending in progress 傳送中
這個步驟可能需要等個一兩天
-幾個小時後
DYDX 代幣都轉到 DYDX 區塊鏈上之後
準備來質疑
這時候會用到 Kepler 錢包
我會把連結放在資訊欄
下載之後 Kepler 錢包就會出現在
Google Chrome 右上的擴充這裡
我們要 Import an existing wallet
輸入現有的錢包
你看它這裡可以 Connect hardware wallet
連結冷錢包
所以你是可以用 Ledger 冷錢包來質疑
這樣更安全
如果金額可能比較大
或者是希望更保險
要買冷錢包的話
我一樣會把冷錢包最大的品牌
Ledger 的購買連結放在資訊欄
要在畢生長期走跳的人
還是會需要一個冷錢包的
不過現在我繼續示範
直接質疑了
我選擇這個 Use Recovery Phrase
或者是 Private Key
用本來就有的私藥
或者是恢復短語
選擇24個字
回到前一步
Bridge.DYDX.Trade
點選右上
然後按 Export Secret Phrase
輸出恢復的短語
這裡會提醒你
千萬不要把這個 Secret Phrase
給任何人知道
不然呢
可能會讓自己暴露在風險裡面
恢復短語
就不要分享給別人好嗎
按 Copy 複製之後呢
來到 Kepler
貼上之後選擇 Import 輸入
接著設定一個名稱
點選螢幕 Google Chrome
右上的這個擴充 Kepler 錢包
Manage Portfolio in Kepler Dashboard
到 Staking 直壓這裡呢
我就會看到
DYDX Staking 跟我的這個 DYDX 代幣
按 Stake 直壓
這裡我就會看到
很多不同的 Validator
也就是驗證者
我可以選擇
把代幣直壓在幾個不同的 Validator
不同的驗證者之下
注意啊
這個 Commission 是驗證者
會跟你收的佣金
所以選擇
不要收太高的這些驗證者
好 我選了三個不同的 Validator
把我的這個代幣直壓進去
畫面右上
立刻可以看到
目前我的這個 USDC 獎勵
按 Claim 立刻就可以開始提領囉
DYDX is one of the few projects
which is a profitable project
and the project profits
is going to the stakers
so if you stake DYDX
on the DYDX chain
you can get essentially a stream
of USDC which are the trading fees
I've never seen that before in crypto
Yeah, it is very, very unique
This is a big difference
with some staking experience
in some other chains
so if you stake for example
on any chain
for the most part
you get paid with a token
from the chain
and usually this token
is high inflation
so you need to quickly
either restake or sell it
on DYDX
you get paid in USDC
there is no urgency to sell it
or you can use it
in many, many more ways
and that's a very exciting experience
and this can be done
just with your ledger
hardware wallet for example
or you can use some exchanges
I think OKEx announced publicly
a few weeks ago
that they are in the process
of integrating DYDX as well
so I suppose OKEx users
will be able to stake
also their DYDX
from the OKEx ecosystem
and collect as well USDCs
You mentioned DYDX token
I think a lot of people
are talking about
how they're concerned
about the unlocking schedule
of DYDX
Can you tell us
a little more on this?
Absolutely
there is no change
of numbers of DYDX
since the DYDX
kind of migrated away
from Ethereum
and created the new chain
so the new
DYDX chain
does not mean more DYDX
the Ethereum DYDX
are migrating
so people can migrate
away from Ethereum
to the DYDX chain
but there is no change
in inflation
there is regular unlocks
from the protocol itself
which is essentially
feeding the community
treasury of DYDX
so the community treasury
of DYDX
community
represents today about
750 million USD
which are available
for the community
to deploy for grants
for DAOs
for supporting
various strategic initiatives
in the ecosystem
so it's also a very wealthy
and long-term thinking
type of ecosystem
with the right resources
the unlock are programmatic
so you can see them coming
and there was an unlock
in December
from the original investors
in DYDX
which I think went in a very
as transparent as possible
and we've seen a lot of these
early investors
also migrating
to the DYDX chain
we have today
a large majority of tokens
which have already migrated
to the DYDX chain
to support the growth of the chain
so you don't see the unlock schedule
impacting the price
how do you actually
comfort people
when they're worried about
how it's going to impact
if they hold DYDX long-term?
that's a good question
there is unlock
in many different ways
on every blockchain
as what is important
is to be able to
see it coming
and understanding it
there is Bitcoin
new Bitcoin
being minted
every seven minutes
on Bitcoin
this is some kind of
soft and slow unlock
on Ethereum
you've got also
an inflation
as well as a dynamic
of Ethereum burning
that's also some soft
and slow unlock
everything has
for the most part
unlocks
there is unlocks
on DYDX
but they are transparent
and visible
so I think people can just
consider and study it
but I don't think
there is anything
very different
from any other systems
you can start your journey
within DYDX
with the DYDX
foundation website
where you get access
to the documentation
and get a better understanding
of the unlocks
it's very transparent
so people can build
their own opinion
from that fairly easily
so just on a personal level
if there's a friend of yours
that you know
is first or new in crypto
would you actually recommend them
to use this staking
or trading reward system?
I will not invite anyone
to DYDX
without any experience
in crypto or trading
remember it's a protocol
for crypto derivative
so the crypto derivative
are more complex crypto products
DYDX is not for your sister
or your cousin
which just discovered
Bitcoin two weeks ago
it's something which is
much more complex
so it's better to
educate the people rightly
being a staker on DYDX
I think is probably
more simple
and approachable
the trading experience
and understanding
derivative trading
is something for
more kind of experienced users
staking isn't the only way
to earn rewards right?
there's also this
Chaos Labs incentive program
so at DYDX
there is two types of rewards
kind of redirected
to the users themselves
so whenever you trade
you get essentially
an immediate reward
in DYDX tokens
in size of your trade
there is also rewards
which are made
for the market makers
or kind of power users
where this time
there will be a point system
so essentially
this kind of incentive program
evaluating
via Chaos Labs services
the kind of activity
and level of activities
and contributions
of different power users
and market makers
and reward them accordingly
after the approval
of Bitcoin Spot ETF
there are a lot of
institutional investors
interested in crypto now
I think people are worried
these big companies
are essentially centralized
for example
BlackRock is huge
they can actually have
a big impact on Bitcoin
what's your take on this?
that's a good question
I like decentralization
I'm a builder of decentralization
but I'm also a cognizant
that many people don't care
most users don't care
about decentralization
you want to have
a healthy product
and functional product
you want to have
ease of access
for some people
buying Bitcoin directly
and keeping it
on their wallet is easy
for some others
there is no way
they're going to be
involved with that
it's normal to have
some kind of core
of early users
with very strong ideas
but when the technology
evolves and grows
the audience
and the people
involved with this technology
comes from different horizons
with different objectives
so adding bigger
and bigger players
in space
we've seen that before
we see the centralized exchanges
being extremely powerful
in our space also
so if people are
a little bit worried
about BlackRock
for example
you should also consider
and review your opinion
about Coinbase
or Binance
or some of these giants
think of FTX
which was a very big player
when they collapse
they impact the market
also greatly
so it's not coming
and this phenomenon
does not start
with the Bitcoin ETF
and I think it's just
a testament
of the additional usage
and bringing different paths
for people to approach crypto
it's a normal kind of path
of growth of the technology
you just mentioned
some of the bigger players
in centralized exchange
and they have very complicated
relationship
with governments
and regulators
what is the relationship
between DYDX
and how do they interact
with different governments
and regulators
if you want to map
the DYDX ecosystem
there is first and foremost
the users
and the community
of DYDX
this represents
tens of thousands
of people
which are token holders
validators
stakers
builders
market makers
we highlight this ecosystem
in the DYDX foundation
ecosystem report
and below this community
which is voting
and deciding
on how to deploy
this open source software
there is different entities
we have the DYDX grants DAO
which is giving grants
to people building on DYDX
there is also the
DYDX operation DAO
which is running
some core services
for the DYDX chain
there is the DYDX foundation
which I represent today
there is also DYDX trading
which is a company
funded by Antonio Giuliano
all these entities
are totally independent
and they essentially work
and kind of follow
the guidance
of the token holders
expressed via the governance
the relationship
with regulators
is happening
on multiple fronts
in many different ways
I think regulators
have more and more
an appetite to understand
the technology of DeFi
as we mentioned earlier
in this conversation
central banks
are starting to use CBDCs
are starting to use
smart contracts
for swapping CBDCs
of different currencies
they really understand
more and more things
and it's a mistake
regulators are only coming
in one kind of type
which is like punishing
people around
many of them are proactive
and welcoming conversations
it's part of our responsibility
as industry practitioners
to engage with regulators
and not only claiming
DeFi is better
but demonstrating
that's a very big difference
demonstrating
that actually
what DeFi can provide
is overlapping
and supporting
what the regulators
want to achieve
regulators want
healthy marketplace
transparency
regulators want
efficient markets
the technology of DeFi
can provide that
by design
since the beginning
very different
than regulating
an exchange
for example
it's more complex
also because
you cannot regulate
one company
it's decentralized
open source software
but I think
it's our responsibility
to engage
and remain engaged
with validators
and demonstrate
that the agenda
of the regulators
and the features
of DeFi
are matching
so there is
multiple conversations
in multiple ways
eventually I think
what regulators
are converging
or what they should
be considering
more
not regulate
the technology
because it's not possible
you cannot regulate
technology
internet
you cannot regulate
Bitcoin
you cannot very hardly regulate
you can regulate
the operators
the people giving access
to this technology
so the same way
there is regulations
for internet service providers
for banks
which give you access
to financial markets
or give you access
to stock exchange
for example
I think it's important
to define some rules
because the rules
are different
in different countries
to essentially
the operators of DeFi
and people giving access
and my bet
for the future
is that a lot
of centralized exchanges
will get licenses
in different countries
most of the time
this license
will be only for trading spots
and they will not be able
to offer derivatives
and I see
part of a future
where centralized exchanges
will be coming
to access DeFi
and kind of facilitate access
to DeFi protocols
via their centralized exchanges
so the same way
today your bank
the core business
of your bank
is to essentially
work with your money
so you get paid
every month
your salary
you put it at the bank
and then the bank
helps you to manage
this money
and then the bank
offers you
and package together
many different products
from many different
other companies
your bank is
most of the time
not an insurance company
but you can buy
insurance from the bank
your bank is not
a stock broker
but they give you access
to stock exchange
and so on
so I think
we see in the distribution
of finance
access points to finance
through the banks
and I think in DeFi
we're going to see
probably something similar
where we're going to see
different service providers
in finance
starting to give access
to DeFi
and facilitate the experience
for the users
and regulators
should be considering
to regulate
and help these operators
to provide this service
in a healthy way
regulating the technology
has never happened
and will hardly happen anywhere
it took regulators
five to ten years
to understand
that the internet
was not
as the technology
could not be regulated
and then they started
to design
only after
some regulations
for the operators
themselves
so regulate
the operator
but do not
regulate the technology
otherwise we kind of
cool down the innovation
and that's something
which is now
a global phenomenon
and it's all really exciting
I feel like
DYDX is doing
a lot of big plans
big things
and what do you think
we can expect
as users
any plans
for 2024
expect more
trading pairs
and new markets
on DYDX
we can see that
via the number
of votes on the chain
I know some people
are working
on mobile apps
making sure
they get available
on the iPhone world
as well as
the Android world
and some great
and better
and better experience
for stakeholders
as well
so the flexibility
the more rewards
to the stakeholders
and that's something
super exciting
as a protocol
we are already
integrated with Ledger
so that's already
to connect
with DYDX
in a safe way
so we expect here
that there is
a lot of more
additional integrations
coming up
the operation
DAO of DYDX
has support in Chinese
so if you have questions
the software
the DAO of DYDX
is helping Chinese users
in Chinese language
to understand more
we will be also
joining some events
in the region
so we want to connect
with all of you guys
at their use
crypto conferences
looking forward
to connect with you
thank you so much
Charles
I find this so insightful
and personally
I've learned a lot
from you
and super inspirational
thank you
thanks for having me
and see you
on the DYDX chain
Thank you
you can see here
you can use the link
to LINE
and Discord
and join the group
and do it
with all of you
we do it
in OKExpn
and other
big exchange
to do it
to the best
20% off
of the
cash flow
payment
and do it
to the link
your cash flow
will get lower
and do it
you can see
you do
next time
do it
!